Md Omar Faruq

iOS Engineer

Address: 26/A, 18 Road, C Block, Mirpur 12, Dhaka. Mobile

No: 01642031736

E-mail: faruqdeveloper@gmail.com

ABOUT

In order to prove oneself as a significant apprentice and extremely strong person and in the field of computer science and engineering one has to face any challenge of such an institution.

I am an iOS software engineer, with 1 year experience in creating iPhone and iPad applications. I have been programming for the last 5 years including iOS SDK, C, QT Symbian, Swift, Swift UI, Assembler and Web Development

EXPERIENCE

iOS Engineer · Jr Consulting

MAY 2020 - PRESENT · Australia

- Built v1 fully using Swift and v2 using UIKit.
- Implemented a scalable Firebase backend with end-to-end database encryption, storage, and cloud functions.

iOS Engineer · Leotech

NOVEMBER 2019 - APRIL2020 · Kawran Bazar Dhaka

- Built fully using SwiftUI and Json APIs.
- Developed Bangladesh landmark for a mobile app

Web Developer · Jr Consulting

MAY 2020 · Australia

- · Language php (Font-End)
- Designing ,Development and Deployment (full work)

AWARDS

2019 Scholar · ICT Ministry

JUN 2019 · Dhaka ,Bangladesh

- Awarded a student scholarship to attend ict Ministry 2019
- Developed interactive Swift Playground using SpriteKit.
- Networked with iOS engineers and designers about the latest in iOS development and received feedback on my apps.



EDUCATION

City University · Computer Science
April 2015 - MAY 2019 · Dhaka Bangladesh
GPA 2.64 · B.Sc in Engineering

APPS



Bangladesh Landmarks

Most recently released app built using SwiftUI and featured on the App Store with over 1,000 users.

SKILS

Proficient

Xcode · Swift · SwiftUI · Firebase . APIs

Experience

Java · Python · Git

Familiar

HTML · CSS · .Bootstrap.php · javascript .Mysql.Sql.Figma

INTERESTS

Rubik's Cube Speedsolving · PC Building · Fitness